<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="dadweek" formatted="false">
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000>This week begins with the last days of my Mom‘s menstrual period. I am nowhere on the scene. But you know I am in the thoughts of God. Let me start my story from here. Let me dedicate this week to Mom and call it Mom‘s week. Are you with me Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Even before we start our journey together let me warn you about my likes and dislikes. I like plenty of fruits and vegetables and I dislike smoking and alcohol. Tell this to everyone at home. &lt;br>&lt;br>I like simple exercises like going for long walks. Take mom for short walks Daddy. Well for time being let me keep my big mouth shut. I don‘t know you; you don‘t know me either. Hey dad, are you planning something? I can see it on your face. Wait you‘ll have a lot to do. I assure you. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000>It is the second week and I am still in the thoughts of God. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Mom’s uterus is preparing a lush new bed of blood – rich tissue for me. One of the ripened eggs is getting ready to be released. Oops! I have started using medical terms. Hope they are not too difficult for you to understand. &lt;br>&lt;br> God has a plan for my life. He is sending me to you with a purpose. Yes Dad, my life is purpose driven. I am not an accident. Towards the end of this week, provided mom has a regular cycle, I‘ll need a little cooperation from you too. Ooo… I‘m so excited! A week more and I‘ll be there. Daddy in a while you would be getting another promotion as I enter the scene. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000>The real drama begins now. Dad sent many sperms inside mom, but only one intrepid one, the fastest of all swimmers that were vying for that single egg of mom‘s … yes only one could penetrate its outer layer and has fertilized it. God has enabled the first step of my journey. Whatever physical or mental shape I am going to acquire tomorrow will be credited to you both Dad and mom. But you Dad will wholly determine my sex. Mom has nothing to do with it. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Congratulations on your small step towards making a great Human – it’s me! You are not going to be alone any more.bI am going to bring about a lot of changes in Mom physically and emotionally. Make sure you handle her well. Are you ready for the journey? &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> The Blastocyst reaches the uterus and searches for a spot to settle down. Some call it the sprout bag. I call it my first home. The cells in the Blastocyst have begun to divide into two groups – those that form the placenta and those that form ―me. I measure only 0.1-0.2 mm in diameter. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>In case Mom is expecting herr periods let me tell you, she will not get it. She is pregnant now. She might feel restless, fatigue and have mood swings. Support her Dad things will shortly change for the better. &lt;br>&lt;br> Is Mom kind of peculiar these days? Well it‘s partly my doing. I will take the blame for it. But you played your role too. So be kind to her – try to understand the responsibility she has to bear these days. She has to take care of not only you but me as well. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Oh Boy I am changing fat these days. I can hardly recognize myself. The developing ―me has three layers now. The top layer (ectoderm will be my nervous system i.e. the brain and spinal chord. The middle layer (mesoderm) will develop into the heart and circulatory system. For the development of intestines, liver, pancreas and bladder it is the lower layer or the endoderm that helps. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> I know Mom‘s mood swings are continuing. Is she throwing temper tantrums too? Well, well, that‘s only the beginning! As I grow with each passing day, she also keeps changing. Be a little patient Dad and I am sure Mom will appreciate that later. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> What‘s that funny faint sound? Oh my! It‘s actually coming from inside me – ‗ lub – dub – lub – dub‘. Bless my heart – they are my first heartbeats. Well, about time too – do you know how big I am now? I am about 1/17th of an inch (0.2 cm) my eyes and ears and a little opening in the mouth as well. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>Mom is going through a little more of nausea and morning sickness. A craving for certain foods is becoming more irresistible to her. &lt;br>&lt;br> You‘ll have to help mom maintain a healthy diet. Keep her away from certain smells that make her uneasy and be a friend who cares. Easier said than done, I know. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am nearly the size of a grain of rice. Do I see a small smile on your face? No jokes – I am growing fast! My arms and legs can now be seen. My brain is growing too, getting bigger with each passing day. It’s boom time for the eyes, nostrils, intestines and pancreas as well. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Mom has started to put on weight. Let her not feel bad about it. It’s not just her but me too. &lt;br>&lt;br>I can see you are not doing too badly now. I even heard you tell your friend the other day about me. Great! I kind of like you already! &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000>Hey, do you know what I got this week? I got my elbows and my fingers. You think that‘s all? No, no, I‘ve got ears, eyes, teeth buds and the tip of the nose as well. What do you think of that now? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>I know Mom is worried about her looks – for those pimples and other skin problems she is getting. Make her understand that they are happening due to an increase in oil secretions. &lt;br>&lt;br> I like the way you accompany mom everywhere these days. I like it, believe me, especially when the three of us go to the doctor. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000>I am around 3.1 cm by now, nearly the size of an olive. Something new is happening within me everyday. I can actually feel it in my bones and cartilage. I am beginning to get eyes and a small little tongue. The intestines are coming out of the umbilical cord and getting into my abdomen. That almost tickles me you know! The fingers and thumbs have appeared but are too tiny. I wish I could grow faster. This is taking a bit too long for my liking! &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> My home, Mom’s uterus has become the size of a grape fruit now. She gets some heartburn and indigestion trying to adjust to the pregnancy hormones. Ask Mom to take a little rest; that makes me feel really good. &lt;br>&lt;br> Is morning sickness becoming more common than the morning tea? Cool it dad, after all you have to take the bad with the good. Mom is looking pretty isn‘t she? &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000>I am about 4.6 cm by now and weigh around 5 gms. The joints guiding my internal movements are almost formed. And I have started moving inside my home. Shh. don‘t tell mom, she doesn‘t know that yet. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> The occasional dizziness accompanied by those headaches – are getting her down. Blame it all on those wild hormones. &lt;br>&lt;br> Veins are appearing on her tummy, breasts and the legs. I can see them. Don‘t let that bother her. As the blood volume inside you increases, they develop. &lt;br>&lt;br>Dad, what are you thinking? One moment I see you staring quizzically at mom – your eyebrows all knitted, shoulders hooked and the next moment I see the little smile on the corner of your mouth. I know – you‘ve begun to get a feel of ensuing fatherhood &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000>I am around 6 cm by now and weigh around 8 gms. By now I have got all the characteristics of a fetus. The most critical part of my development is over. The placenta has started to develop and blood has started to circulate between my mom‘s uterus and me. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> I bet you Mom is feeling slightly better this week. Although certain smells still bother her, the nausea has subsided a bit and her appetite is increased. I know it because I wasn‘t hungry this week. Her uterus can be felt in her lower abdomen. &lt;br>&lt;br> Now that mom is feeling better, why don‘t we all go on a short trip? That way you can take a break too. Mind you no rash driving. It might affect me in some way. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 6.3 cm by now and I weigh around 8 to 14 Gms. Hey want some good news? I can pee now! Nearly all my organs are formed now. Fingers and toes have separated and hair and nails have begun to grow. Gosh – my gender is no more a secret! &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> There‘s good news for Mom. The uterus is shifting forward as it grows, but it won‘t press on her bladder much. So those bathroom visits will get less frequent. That‘s good news isn‘t it? Morning sickness is also better. But she is going to gain weight in her hips and legs. I know the headaches are bothering her now. &lt;br>&lt;br> Do you want to hear my heartbeats? You can use a Doppler for that. Ask the doctor next time you take mom there. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 7.4 cm by now and I weigh around 23 gms. My eyes and ears are continuing to develop. My neck is getting longer! I can see the room I am staying in. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Hey Dad Mom should start taking vitamins along with a healthy diet. Do you know something? I only get vitamins from what she eats. I know you are so excited to hear about this. Daddy get nutritious food that would help Mom to increase her nutritional values. Tell her that it’s for me! Ha ha ha.. &lt;br>&lt;br> Getting ready to go for shopping? Give me some more time. I‘ll be right there with you for a jolly go ride. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 8.7 cm by now and I weigh around 43 Gms Oops I have doubled my weight. I think you are doing great job together in taking care of me. My bones are getting harder and stronger. My skin is still transparent and it really bothers me so much. Very fine hair is covering my body. This will shed only prior to my birth. It helps me to protect my skin. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Mom might have some discomfort because of this growth in my body. Just few more weeks to go. You know something? If Mom is more than 35 years old, the Doctors will test her for Down‘s syndrome. Cool!! God is in control. Don’t have negative thoughts. Everything is going to be fine when God is with us. &lt;br>&lt;br> You are doing a great job as father. I can see how you are cooperating with mom. You have stopped seeing at mom as just mom but as me and mom! That‘s great! Do you know how much that excites me? I am so happy for you both. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 10.1 cm by now and I weigh around 70 Gms. I have started to move around. Mom can feel my presence every now and then. The three tiny bones in my ears have begun to harden. My eyebrows are beginning to grow. I am becoming beautiful as I always am. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Moms heart is increasing its output to supply me with oxygen. Her heart is pumping about 20% more blood than pre - pregnancy. This volume would increase throughout her pregnancy for an ending increased heart output of 30-50%. If her clothes are getting tight, get her maternity clothes. Remember I am growing!! Which means its ok for mom to grow. &lt;br>&lt;br> If mom is raiding your closet for clothes, you are not alone. However, there are products out there that you can try to help her extend the life of her pre-pregnancy clothes that don't involve pins, rubber bands or stealing your clothes! &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 11.6 cm by now and I weigh around 100 Gms. This is a week of ―mights. Mom might hear the tiny thumps of my heart with an external monitor now. The genitals are developed sufficiently that an experienced sonographer might be able to determine if I am a boy or a girl. Be it a boy or a girl you are going to love me isn’t it? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Mom might begin to feel my movement around this point. This is more likely to happen now if you already had a child before me or if Mom is very thin.These first movements are called ―quickening. They can also be used in helping to determine Mom’s due date. I am not going to stay still anymore. &lt;br>&lt;br> Have you been to a prenatal appointment recently? It might be nice to try to go again; it's been about a month since you've first heard my heart beat. Think of it as a nice chance to sneak away for lunch together and to celebrate me. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 13 cm by now and I weigh around 140 Gms. I now have much more human appearance. My body limbs are larger in proportion to my head. Oops Meconium (digestive secretion and swallowed amniotic fluid) has started to gather. &lt;br>&lt;br> Umbilical cord is getting stronger. My skeleton is transforming from cartilage to bone. The bone still remains flexible to make the journey through the birth canal easier. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Mom’s secretions all over your body may increase, due to the increased blood volume. Sweating more, have nasal congestion, or suffering from increased vaginal discharge tor few symptoms Mom will have. Help her during these discomforts Daddy. &lt;br>&lt;br> Do you know if there are any expectant dad classes in your area? You might try calling the hospital, birth centre or local childbirth educators to find out if you could be educated on this. Hope this book helps you Dad! &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 14.2 cm by now and I weigh around 190 Gms. Vernix (a white cheese – like protective material) is forming on my skin to protect my skin during the months in water. See how creative my shepherd is! Tiny air sacs have begun to form in my lungs. I will be putting my lungs to good use in just a few months. I can go through a motion of crying but without air I cannot make sound. Fast growth this week which means tired week for Mom! &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Do not forget to give Mom prenatal vitamins! Sleeping may be increasingly difficult now, as her body grows. Try supporting by buying her maternity pillows. If you haven't started yet, try playing around with baby names. Look through your family history, read books, look at combinations for girls and boys. And if you have a promise from God name me in faith. &lt;br>&lt;br> Don‘t tell mom that she is trying to look fat. She is looking cute with me right. It‘s not mom alone now but both of us together. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 15.3 cm by now and I weigh around 240 Gms. I now have the same awake and sleep patterns of a new born. I have a favourite position for sleep and recognizable active and rest periods. Mom would be able to find it out. Milk teeth buds have already developed and over the next few days buds for the permanent teeth will begin to form behind it. In case I am a girl, my uterus starts to develop this week. If I am a boy the genitals are now distinct and recognizable. You know something? I am swallowing amniotic fluid and my kidneys are making urine. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> If you have not looked into childbirth classes now is the time to do so. Child birth education is a great way of informing yourself about pregnancy, labor and birth. There are many different types of classes available and many different types of teachers. Find a class that best fits her schedule. Some classes meet for a few hours every week for several weeks, while other meet for an intense period of time over one or two days. &lt;br>&lt;br> Mom may start asking you if you feel me move. Invariably you either can't feel me yet or I quit moving as soon as you put your hand on me. This is very normal. Most people can't feel the baby move from the outside until around week 28. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 16.4 cm by now and I weigh around 300 Gms. I am half way there. The rapid growth stage is over. Even though things have slowed down, this next stage is vital to survival. The nerve cells for taste, smell, hearing, seeing and touch are now developing in specialized areas of the brain. I can actually hear noises outside the womb. If I am a girl I now have approximately six million eggs in my ovaries and about one million would remain at birth. My creator is very creative. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Help her find a quiet place so that she can lay flat on her back. Locate her heart beat by finding her pulse. Next lay your hand on her belly. You would be able to distinguish between my heart beat and Mom’s. As muscles are developing she would be able to feel my kicks even stronger. I can listen to sounds. Familiar voices, music and sounds that I become accustomed to during developmental stages often are calming at birth. Watch out for what you hear. &lt;br>&lt;br> Take mom out to dinner to celebrate the half-way point in pregnancy. A gift for the baby is also a nice touch. This is particularly true if you're just finding out if I am a girl or a boy. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 26.7 cm by now and I weigh around 360 Gms. White blood cells are under production in my body. They help in fighting infections and diseases. My skin has become more opaque. My tongue is fully formed. I am swallowing amniotic fluid. I am putting myself into digestion practice. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Everyone is probably telling you what sex your baby is using different myths! Some people find this fun, others find it annoying. Using things like how you carry, what you eat, the Chinese Gender Chart, or other myths are fun, but not always accurate. Have you decided whether you want to find out the gender of your baby? There are many things to consider before doing so, and still I may not cooperate. &lt;br>&lt;br> Don’t be worried about my gender Dad. It was decided by your contribution and don’t ever forget it. Be it a boy or a girl I am going to be the apple of your eye. Yes Dad we are soon going to spend time together as I emerge out of my first home! &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 27.8 cm by now and I weigh around 430 Gms. I can now hear your conversations more clearly than before. When you talk, read or sing remember I am hearing you. My eye lids and eye brows are fully formed. Finger nails have grown. &lt;br>&lt;br> My brain has entered a stage of rapid growth. Why don’t you keep singing His praises to me? My heart would rejoice to do that Mom. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Mom is still looking pretty good and active in this second trimester. Appreciate her Dad. If she is still having aches and pains or feel like she is slowing down you should look into some different remedies for the problems she is experiencing. With God’s strength she can do it well Dad. It’s time to pray with her now. &lt;br>&lt;br> Have you packed on a few pounds since the beginning of pregnancy? If so you are not alone. Many dads do put on some weight along with mom. You might also experience other symptoms of pregnancy. Be cool Daddy after all it’s a part of receiving me into your life. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 28.9 cm by now and I weigh around 501 Gms. I almost look like a new born but I am thinner. I am able to hear. My eyes are formed. I have begun producing Insulin, important for breakdown of sugars. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Mom might begin to feel my movement around this point. This is more likely to happen now if you already had a child before me or if she are very thin. &lt;br>&lt;br> It is not uncommon for first time mothers to not recognize fetal movements until 22-24 weeks. These first movements are called ―quickening. They can also be used in helping to determine the due date. I am not going to stay still anymore. &lt;br>&lt;br> Mom may actually feel Braxton kick contradictions, or she might just happen to notice with her hand a slight tensing of her abdomen. This is just her uterine muscle preparing for birth. The uterus actually contracts at all phases of a woman's life, however, we rarely notice this unless our uterus is full! Be with mom during these days. It would be a great comfort! &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 30 cm by now and I weigh around 600 Gms almost a length of a ruler. My body begins to fill out with my appearance more like a new born. My taste buds are beginning to form. Over the next seven days sweat gland will be forming in the skin. This week I am officially considered viable. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Mom is now aware of my movements and she might even be able to tell my sleep/wake cycles. It is important to recognize the signs of premature labour. Premature labour is actually more common in the summer months, thought to be caused by dehydration in some women, so ask Mom to continue drinking lots of water! &lt;br>&lt;br> Mom is now visibly pregnant for most everyone to notice. You may feel a swell of pride when talking about her and the new baby. This is a normal feeling. &lt;br>&lt;br> And Dad everybody is now asking you about my arrival soon right? Be proud of your God given blessing. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 34.6 cm by now and I weigh around 660 Gms. Structures of my spine have begun to form. Blood vessels of the lungs are developing. My nostrils have begun to open. My swallowing reflexes are developing. I can now make a fist and can clasp objects placed in my palm. I am excited I am learning to do new things. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> At this point in pregnancy mom might probably still feel really good! Soon you will begin to see your practitioner more often. When this happens, many women begin to get the feeling that they are running out of time. &lt;br>&lt;br>Fixing my room or deciding where I sleep, is one of the things you need to work out together now. &lt;br>&lt;br>If you have opinions about things that relate to baby - speak up! Sometimes mom has a tendency to just give her opinion. Maybe she's asked and you've clammed up? Don't bother, just share what your opinion is on raising baby. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 35.6 cm by now and I weigh around 760 Gms. Air sacs in my lungs are forming now. My eyes are opening and beginning to blink this week. Retinas begin to form. My brain wave activity for hearing and sight begins to be detectable. &lt;br>&lt;br> If you shine a light on your abdomen mom, I will turn my head, which means my optic nerve is working. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> While Mom has been feeling movements for a while, Dad you may not have been able to. Around this time it may become possible for you to begin feeling me from the outside. It is really nice to share the experience together right? &lt;br>&lt;br> Finding a comfortable position for sleeping is a new task for Mom! A body pillow will enable her to support her legs and her growing belly! If she doesn’t have one, try to get her one. Some dads choose to sleep elsewhere to avoid disturbances to their sleep, including the many trips to the bathroom Mom makes each night. This should be discussed together. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 36.6 cm by now and I weigh around 875 Gms. My brain continues its rapid growth. My hearing continues to develop. I have started to recognize your voice and Mom‘s Dad! That‘s interesting right? My lungs are continuing to grow and prepare for functioning outside of the womb. I am continuing to take small breaths. My eye lids are now open more. This week alone I will grow over 1 inch. Oops I am faster now! &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Dad you can now share music, conversation and even books with me. Welcome Mom to the third trimester. The home stretch! Around this time mom will begin to really put on the weight, this will last until about week thirty-six. Although some cultures dictate otherwise, weight gained during pregnancy is not fat or unhealthy, but rather, necessary for a healthy pregnancy and baby. &lt;br>&lt;br>The weight that she gains will be distributed in several places. If mom is starting to complain about her weight remind her of the importance of weight gain in pregnancy for a health pregnancy. You should also help her by not tempting her with sweets and setting a good example yourself. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 37.6 cm by now and I weigh around 1 Kg. My eye brows and eye lashes are now very noticeable. Hair on my head is growing longer. Some babies are born with almost none at all, while others appear to be ready for their first hair cut. My eyes are completely formed now. My body is getting plump and rounded. Lungs are capable of breathing now. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> You can talk to me often, read stories, and sing songs and so on. I can recognize your voice now and will often calm to it later on. Keep talking to me. I really love that. &lt;br>&lt;br> Have you been to a prenatal appointment recently? It might be nice to try to go again; it's been about a month since you've first heard my heart beat. Think of it as a nice chance to sneak away for lunch together and to celebrate me. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 38.6 cm by now and I weigh around 1153 Gms. My head is in proportion with my body now. Fat continues to accumulate under my skin. My brain can control primitive breathing and body temperatures. My eyes can move in their sockets. I am increasingly sensitive to changes in light, sound, taste and smell! I am now moving from side to side. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> As I have started to move sometimes mom might even wonder thinking that I am performing somersaults for a circus act. As your baby is growing, so is your body. She might feel as if her internal organs are crowded. They are. &lt;br>The best way to deal with the ―discomforts of pregnancy is &lt;br>• Good Posture &lt;br>• Proper Nutrition &lt;br>• Exercise &lt;br>• Rest (When she could!) &lt;br>Most discomforts will occur in her back, her legs, and the amount of air she can take into her lungs. Hang in there! &lt;br>Have you rubbed her back? You might even consider a professional pregnancy massage. It makes a great gift. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 39.9 cm by now and I weigh around 1319 Gms. My head is getting larger to accommodate a period of rapid brain growth. As I grow and fill Mom’s uterus, the amount of amniotic fluid will decrease. Mom won‘t feel lighter any more. I spend more time practicing opening and closing my eye lids. My toe nails are entering into final growth stage. Bone marrow is now producing red blood cells. I now have the capacity to produce tears – within the womb. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Mom’s posture is still very important to her comfort. Maintaining a good posture is a good way to decrease the strain on her body as her centre of gravity continues to change. One of the things that she can do to help maintain her energy levels and to increase her stamina for the birth is to exercise. &lt;br>&lt;br> Try taking Mom for walks or swimming short distances. Getting out and stretching will help her feel better and reduce the numbers of pregnancy related complaints. &lt;br>&lt;br> Take notes in childbirth class. Write down what you think is most important for you to remember. Don't suffer from information overload. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 41.1 cm by now and I weigh around 1502 Gms. The rate of my physical growth slows down. Even though I don‘t grow much longer, my weight keeps increasing. Fat continues to accumulate. Calcium, Phosphorus and iron being stored in my body and my bones are growing and hardening. My brain has entered another period of rapid growth, producing hundreds of billions of nerve cells! Amazing! I may move to the rhythm of music. Lungs are the only major organs left to complete development. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Mom’s abdomen swells and her rib cage and pelvis may be sore as I get bigger and fill up all the space she has available. While it is really great that I am gaining weight and growing strong, mom might be in line for different discomforts at this stage of the game, like heart burn and leg cramps &lt;br>&lt;br>A few women will breeze by even this phase of pregnancy without any discomforts. This does not mean that your body isn't preparing for birth. It could be pain tolerance levels, exercise and agility levels and many other factors. So, count your blessings if Mom falls into this category! &lt;br>&lt;br>Don't forget to plan for traffic, special parades, having gas and even car keys. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 42.4 cm by now and I weigh around 1702 Gms. All my senses (all the 5) are now working. I am fascinated and practicing testing these out as much as possible. Hair on my head continues to grow in. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> I want to address the last question specifically. About 10% of women will tell you that labour is extremely painful, while 10% of the women will tell you that they experienced no pain. The rest, 80%, will fall someplace in the middle of the two extremes. &lt;br>&lt;br> But don‘t worry Dad, ―God is with mom as a mighty terrible one. She can cross this valley happily with God’s grace. Just be with her in prayers. &lt;br>&lt;br> Are you waiting to see whose type of hair I would be having during my birth? Just wait for some more time. Are you ready for baby? What do you have left to do? Sit down and make a list of things that are left to be done before the birth. Do you have a car seat? Have you picked a paediatrician? &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 43.7 cm by now and I weigh around 1918 Gms. My head size has increased 3/8ths of an inch due to rapid brain growth. Neurons and synapses are developing in huge numbers – forming connections in my brain will give me the skills I need to thrive as a new born. This week I may be able to coordinate sucking and swallowing with breathing. My skull is quite pliable and not completely joined. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Mom can now probably distinguish my knee from and elbow, even though the movements are smaller. Mom might also notice small bumps that appear to be rhythmic in her uterus. This is probably caused by me having hiccoughs and isn't cause for alarm &lt;br>&lt;br>Don't forget to spend some time practicing relaxation with mom. Try putting on some nice, quiet music and giving her a massage and working on practicing relaxation for birth. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 45cm by now and I weigh around 2146 Gms. I almost behave like a new born now my eyes opened when I am awake and closed when sleeping. I am settled with a regular sleeping time now. I have learned to blink. I have already turned to a head down position in preparation for birth. Finger nails have reached the end of the finger tips. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Do you know something? I can see more clearly when there is a bright light on Mom’s stomach and probably I have the outline of all her organs memorized. Antibodies from her blood are being transferred to me. This bond between us continues till birth. Mom’s body is really getting ready and she might notice that she has more and more contractions that seem less and less like practice! This is a great sign that her body is getting ready! &lt;br>Labour is broken down into three stages: &lt;br>• First stage - contractions that open the cervix. &lt;br>• Second stage - pushing the baby out. &lt;br>• Third stage - birthing the placenta &lt;br>If you haven't done it yet, consider doing a piece of art work that is related to your pregnancy. You can do a photo shoot, paint her belly. It's a great way to spend time together as well as commemorate the pregnancy. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 46.2 cm by now and I weigh around 2383 Gms. Most babies born now will survive and without any long term problems. Fat accumulations plumps up my arms and legs this week. . These layers of fat help me to regulate my body temperature. They also provide that cute little dimple on elbows and knees. My hearing is fully developed. I am now taking up most of the uterus. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Mom might even feel like her chest has run short of room. Soon enough though, I will move down and she will be able to breathe easily. Her pregnancy is progressing and she might have trouble sleeping at night. There are numerous physical reasons that sleep may be difficult. &lt;br>&lt;br> For one going to the bathroom every 45 minutes isn't conducive to sleep, nor is a constant back ache. &lt;br>&lt;br> If you haven't enjoyed playing the kicking game with me, do so now. &lt;br>&lt;br>Typically when you hold your hand on mom's belly you'll feel the baby kick. Try tapping back and see how I respond. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 47.4 cm by now and I weigh around 2622 Gms. The only organ still to mature is the lungs. Each day the baby stays within the womb, it will multiply its chances to breathe on its own. This week I may drop into the birth canal. Skin is growing smooth; call it ―baby soft. I have fully developed pair of kidneys. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> While breathing for mom becomes easier walking may be the exact opposite. Most babies will be in a head down position at this point. However, about 4% of the babies will be breech. &lt;br>&lt;br> Do not panic! There are plenty of things that you can do to encourage the baby to turn, including special exercises. &lt;br>&lt;br> Since her prenatal appointments are every week now, you might want to go with her to check in with her midwife or doctor &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 48.6 cm by now and I weigh around 2859 Gms. I am officially full term now but can still benefit from extra days in the womb. I continue to practice breathing movements. If God gives me some more time for me to jump around your belly I would happily do it Mom. I tell you I love this first home of mine. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> A pregnancy is considered a term pregnancy at this point and nothing will be done to stop labour in most circumstances. You should plan to take a tour of your birth facility if you have not previously. &lt;br>&lt;br> If you are having a home birth try to invite everyone over for a quick run through of what you expect. &lt;br>&lt;br> If you haven't helped her pack her bag for labour or get the house ready. Right now she could go into labour safely at any point. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 49.8 cm by now and I weigh around 3083 Gms. My intestines are accumulating lots of Meconium. Meconium takes on the role of being my first bowel movement – removing the waste that has accumulated. Circumference of head and abdomen are about the same size for me. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Mom might begin to feel electrical buzzes down her legs and inside her vagina. This is caused from me hitting nerves as I settle into her pelvis. &lt;br>&lt;br> It is also usually encouraged that you bring a separate support person for the child (ren) so that they may come and go during labour and you won't be concerned. &lt;br>&lt;br>I know you will not be allowed inside the labour room. But you know something your presence and touch every now and then would be of great comfort to mom. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 50.7 cm by now and I weigh around 3288 Gms. My lungs are maturing and fully I am preparing to take on the outside world. In addition to normal fat, I am accumulating a special ―brown fat in the nape of my neck, between my shoulders and around organs. Brown fat cells are important for thermo genesis (generating heat) during the first weeks. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Now that Mom knows how to tell if she is really in labour, let's talk about some of the ways Mom’s body prepares for labour. I will descend into her pelvis, sometimes called engagement or lightening, usually before labour in first time moms and during labour in subsequent births. &lt;br>&lt;br> Have you ever changed a diaper? You might see if there is a baby you can borrow to experiment on. Seriously, changing diapers is but one thing a dad can do to help a new mom. You can help bathe and snuggle with your baby, consider getting a baby carrier so that you can hold the baby close while you walk around. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 51.2 cm by now and I weigh around 3462 Gms. 15 percent of my body is fat. Since I havent learnt to shiver yet, these fat stores will help in regulating my temperature. Approximately 60 – 75 percent is water! &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>Are you listening Dad? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Congratulations! Any day now you will be cradling your son or daughter! Cherish the moments and learn all you can about this new personality in your life &lt;br>&lt;br> Try to help mom be comfortable and that also means emotionally. Remember that well meaning friends and family will be calling to inquire about mom and baby. Try to answer the phone for her. &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b>&lt;center>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="header">
        <item>&lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#808080>&lt;h3>Hi, mom u r in the&lt;/h3>&lt;/center>&lt;/center>&lt;/font> &lt;h1>1 st Week Now&lt;/h1>&lt;/font></item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="month_arrays">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>4</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>6</item>
        <item>7</item>
        <item>8</item>
        <item>9</item>
        <item>10</item>
        <item>11</item>
        <item>12</item>
        <item>13</item>
        <item>14</item>
        <item>15</item>
        <item>16</item>
        <item>17</item>
        <item>18</item>
        <item>19</item>
        <item>20</item>
        <item>21</item>
        <item>22</item>
        <item>23</item>
        <item>24</item>
        <item>25</item>
        <item>26</item>
        <item>27</item>
        <item>28</item>
        <item>29</item>
        <item>30</item>
        <item>31</item>
        <item>32</item>
        <item>33</item>
        <item>34</item>
        <item>35</item>
        <item>36</item>
        <item>37</item>
        <item>38</item>
        <item>39</item>
        <item>40</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="weekPrayer">
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad, &lt;br>Its time to begin our journey with prayers. Pray for God‘s grace in my life and that I should be set apart according to His purpose in my life &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> “God who separated me from my mother‘s womb and called me by His grace” – Galatians 1:15&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/i> &lt;font color=#000000> I have been talking to you this long. I know you have desires and dreams about me. Please do write it down each week. It will help you to pray for me. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;br> Pray that I should depend on God from these days, even when I am in the womb. I love God and I want to love Him more. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> “From birth I was cast upon you; from my mother‘s womb you have been my God” – Psalms 22:10 &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/i> &lt;font color=#000000> Pray that I would always be after God’s own heart. My life as I grow and live should bring glory to His wonderful name. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;br> Have you heard this verse? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> “The horse is prepared for the battle. But victory is of the Lord” – Proverbs 21:31 &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/i> &lt;font color=#000000> I know you have been planning for quite sometime to have someone like me and you‘ve been trying for it. But you know whatever you try only God can give you ME. After all children are gifts from God. Why don‘t you start making efforts with a prayer? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;br> Now that you have succeeded in you attempts, it will be great for you to have someone like me in your life isn‘t it? I am proud too to have you both. Now that God has granted you both with ―me, I know you will love to start praying for me earnestly. &lt;br> Yes God has given the apple of His eye under your protection. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> “Lo children are an heritage of the Lord: and the fruit of the womb is His reward” – Psalms 127:3.&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;font color=#000000>Now pray that God should take care of every detail of my growth. I know He does it already. But it’s your duty to tell that to Him. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;br> God‘s eyes have seen my unformed body. Please pray that all the parts of my body should develop well and that it should be used for His name‘s glory. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> “Your eyes saw my unformed body. All the days ordained for me were written in your book before one of them came to be” – Psalms 139:16 &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> He has a perfect plan for all my body parts. Do you believe in that? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad, &lt;br> Please pray that my eyes should always be fixed on God the father. Let me look unto Him in all circumstances of my life. Will you do that for me? Also pray that the word of my mouth as I begin to speak should be a pleasing sacrifice to God. And Mom &amp; Dad I would love to be like David who was a man after God‘s own heart. Will you pray that I would be like one? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> “May the words of my mouth and the meditation of my heart be pleasing in your sight, O Lord my rock, and my redeemer” – Psalms 19:14 &lt;br>“I lift up my eyes to the hills where does my help come from?” – Psalms 121: 1 &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;br> Please pray that the works of my hands should be pure. Let me use my hands to praise God. I would like to play musical instruments with my hands and worship God. Why not pray for that in particular? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> “I wash my hands in innocence and go about your altar Oh Lord” - Psalms 26: 6 &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;br> Pray for the development of my fingers. They should be strong to face the battle ahead of me. I would like to have a good handwriting as I go to school. I think it‘s a bit ahead of me to think of it now. I think it‘s ok. And my teeth should be whiter ha ha ha! Will you pray Dad &amp; Mom? &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;b> &lt;font color=#FF0000> “Praise be to the Lord my rock, who trains my hands for war, my fingers for battle” – Psalms 144:1 &lt;br> “His eyes will be darker than wine, his teeth whiter than milk” – Genesis 49:12 &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;br> Pray that I should hold His breathe in me as long as I live. My tongue should utter words that would praise Him and let it keep on uttering His holy scriptures. I would like to grow more in His word. Would you pray for that? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;b> &lt;font color=#FF0000> As long as I have life within me, the breathe of God in my nostrils Job 27:3 &lt;br>My tongue will speak of your righteousness and your praises all day long – Psalms 35:28 &lt;br>May my tongue sing of your word – Psalms 119:172 &lt;br>Before a word is on my tongue, you know it completely Oh Lord– Psalms 139:4 &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;font color=#000000> Now claim these verses as you pray! &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;br> Please pray for me claiming God‘s words. Scripture says that it has the power to penetrate my joins. Let me have a power penetrated first movement. Why don‘t you both pray over me with His promises? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b> &lt;font color=#FF0000>“For the word of God is living and active, sharper than any double edged sword, it penetrates even to dividing soul and spirit, joints and marrow; it judges the thoughts and attitudes of the heart” – Hebrews 4:12 &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;br> I know that all the hairs of my head are numbered. Don‘t worry. God looks at me as the apple of His eye. Keep praying for me with good cheer. Is that ok? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b> &lt;font color=#FF0000> “Indeed the very hairs of your head are all numbered. Don‘t be afraid you are worth more than sparrows” – Luke 12:7&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;font color=#000000>Pray that I have a beautiful hair as I grow. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad, &lt;br> Do not worry about my gender. Whether I am a boy or a girl I mean so much to you right? I was in the thoughts of God and that is why He has given me to you. Remember, &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b> &lt;font color=#FF0000> Psalms 139:14 says, “I praise you because I am fearfully and wonderfully made; your works are wonderful, I know that full well”.&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;font color=#000000>Thank God for the purpose for which I was sent to you. Pray that you would faithfully raise me to fulfil the purpose God has in His mind for me. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;br> I am just reminded of this verse as I proudly look at you when you plan things for my growth. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;font color=#FF0000> If you, then; though you are evil, know how to give good gifts to your children, how much more will your Father in heaven give good gifts to those who ask him! Matt 7:11. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;font color=#964B00> Don‘t worry I will grow to be a big person very soon. I love you both. Pray that I learn to pray and look unto God for all my needs. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br> &lt;b> &lt;font color=#FF0000> Pleasant words are a honeycomb, sweet to the soul and healing to the bones – Proverbs 16:24.&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>Yes! Why don‘t you start speaking kind words to me and as well to others? That would build our bones. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br> &lt;b> &lt;font color=#FF0000> For the word of God is alive and active. Sharper than any double-edged sword, it penetrates even to dividing soul and spirit, joints and marrow; it judges the thoughts and attitudes of the heart – Hebrews 4:12. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>Start speaking Bible verses to me. They would penetrate my joints and marrow! Pray that my bones would become stronger and stronger. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> As a mother comforts her child, so will I comfort you; and you will be comforted over Jerusalem. – Isaiah 66:13. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> That is how God honours motherhood. Yes, we have a long way to go in our life together me, Dad &amp; Mom. As I start moving around pray that God would bless my journey out in the world and that He would guide and guard my steps. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> For I know the plans I have for you, declares the LORD, plans to prosper you and not to harm you, plans to give you hope and a future. – Jeremiah 29:11.&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> God has got a plan for my life. He is bringing the best out of my life. Just wait for God‘s time to see me. &lt;br> This week many things are happening within me. Pray that I would advance into a troop with the strength that He gives me. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> As Psalms 34:10 says, ―He protects all their bones, not one of them will be broken.&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> Pray that all my bones should be protected by the creator even as they begin to grow. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad, &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> As it is said in Psalms 139:2, ―You know when I sit and when I rise you perceive my thoughts from afar.&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> God knows all my emotions. Do pray that God should help me to have emotional stability as I grow. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> As it is said in Song of Solomon 4:2 Your teeth are like a flock of sheep just shorn, coming up from the washing. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> Pray that my teeth should be beautiful. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> According to Galatians 5:22,23, ―But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness and self-control‖,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> pray for these characters to develop in me. Let my emotions bring joy to my Lord! &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> According to Psalms 31:19, which says, ―How great is your goodness, which you have stored up for those who fear you, which you bestow in the sight of all on those who take refuge in you.&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> pray that I should always take refuge in God. And also pray that God would enable you to happily accept me whatever be the gender. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> According to Job 19:27, which says, ―I myself will see him with my own eyes—I, and not another. How my heart yearns within me!&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> Let my eyes have a longing to see God. &lt;br> Pray that my heart is always sensitive to my Father God. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> According to Psalms 139:3, ―You discern my going out and my lying down; you are familiar with all my ways.&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> Pray that God should direct my paths and my actions in life. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> Matthew 18:14 reveals the heartbeat of God. It says, ―In the same way your Father in heaven is not willing that any of these little ones should perish. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> Pray that my heart beat should match with my Creator and that I should always do His will. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;br> &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> As it is written in Psalms 150:6, ―Let everything that has breath praise the LORD. Praise the LORD.&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> pray that His praise should always be on my lips &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> According 149:3 ―Let them praise his name with dancing and make music to him with timbrel and harp.&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> Pray that I should be a good worshipper of God! &lt;br> Pray that I would sing praises to His wonderful name always and follow Him alone. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> According to Psalms 147:4, which says, ―He determines the number of the stars and calls them each by name,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> you know God has called me by my name. Are you now excited now to decide on my name? &lt;br> Pray that from now on till the end of my life I should hold God’s hands and walk in His ways. He has called be my name and He will lift me up. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> All the hairs of my head are counted. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> Yes that’s what the Bible says. Pray that I am blessed with a beautiful hair. I know God knows what would suit me. &lt;br>Why don’t you pray for how you wish it to be? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> He has made everything beautiful in its time – Ecclesiastes 3:11. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> Yes God is waiting for His time. You know He is wonderfully dealing with me. &lt;br>Don‘t get excited too much. Just wait for His time to see me. Pray that God would meet all the needs for my arrival. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> Trust in the LORD with all your heart and lean not on your own understanding‖ – Proverbs 3:5.&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> Pray that I should grow in the fear of the Lord. &lt;br> More than the talents and gifts I possess its important to have a strong relationship with God. Don’t you think so.&lt;br> Pray that I would have a strong love relationship with God and obey Him completely. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> Hold on to instruction; do not let it go; guard it well, for it is your life‖ – Proverbs 4:13.&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> Pray and ask God that I should be a humble person ready to obey to the voice of God and of course to your instructions. Isn‘t that good to start doing it now? &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> I love those who love me, and those who seek me find me – Proverbs 8:17.&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> Pray that I should be a good seeker. I know I would be able to learn more from your examples. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> Whoever heeds discipline shows the way to life, but whoever ignores correction leads others astray – Proverbs 10:17. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> Pray that God should give me wisdom and grace to accept all disciplines. I want to be a disciplined person like you! &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> May he give you the desire of your heart and make all your plans succeed – Psalms 20:4.&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> Pray that I should be a successful person in life. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> Some trust in chariots and some in horses, but we trust in the name of the LORD our God – Psalms 20:7.&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> Pray that I should always put my trust in God and not on others. &lt;br>I know you are also trusting God only for my safe arrival. I really appreciate that. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> Surely your goodness and love will follow me all the days of my life, and I will dwell in the house of the LORD forever – Psalms 23:6. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> Why don‘t you claim this promise for me and pray together over my life. I would love that. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> My eyes are ever on the LORD, for only he will release my feet from the snare – Psalms 25:15. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#964B00> Pray that my eyes should ever be on him. Start talking about God to me! &lt;br>Try to tell me stories and testimonies of how you got me as a gift from God. &lt;br>Yes Mom and Dad I love to hear you speak to me. I have recorded your voices &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;br> &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;font color=#FF0000> You will keep in perfect peace those whose minds are steadfast, because they trust in you – Isaiah 26:3. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Pray that both of you should have good peace of mind these days. That is a great source of joy for me. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;br> &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;b> &lt;font color=#FF0000> The horse is made ready for the day of battle, but victory rests with the LORD – Proverbs 21:31.&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;font color=#000000>Now you have done all the preparations. Just wait with thanks giving. Wait on the Lord in prayer with thanksgiving. &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Dear Mom and Dad,&lt;br> &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;i>&lt;font color=#FF0000> Hope deferred makes the heart sick, but a longing fulfilled is a tree of life – Proverbs 13:12.&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;font color=#000000>Your long wait has ended. Great! Now lay hands on me pray and bless me &lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br></item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="weekPrayercontent">
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Its time to begin our journey with prayers. Pray for God‘s grace in my life and that I should be set apart according to His purpose in my life “God who separated me from my mother‘s womb and called me by His grace” – Galatians 1:15 I have been talking to you this long. I know you have desires and dreams about me. Please do write it down each week. It will help you to pray for me.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Pray that I should depend on God from these days, even when I am in the womb. I love God and I want to love Him more. “From birth I was cast upon you; from my mother‘s womb you have been my God” – Psalms 22:10 Pray that I would always be after God’s own heart. My life as I grow and live should bring glory to His wonderful name.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Have you heard this verse? “The horse is prepared for the battle. But victory is of the Lord” – Proverbs 21:31 I know you have been planning for quite sometime to have someone like me and you‘ve been trying for it. But you know whatever you try only God can give you ME. After all children are gifts from God. Why don‘t you start making efforts with a prayer?</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Now that you have succeeded in you attempts, it will be great for you to have someone like me in your life isn‘t it? I am proud too to have you both. Now that God has granted you both with ―me, I know you will love to start praying for me earnestly. Yes God has given the apple of His eye under your protection. “Lo children are an heritage of the Lord: and the fruit of the womb is His reward” – Psalms 127:3. Now pray that God should take care of every detail of my growth. I know He does it already. But it’s your duty to tell that to Him.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, God‘s eyes have seen my unformed body. Please pray that all the parts of my body should develop well and that it should be used for His name‘s glory. “Your eyes saw my unformed body. All the days ordained for me were written in your book before one of them came to be” – Psalms 139:16 He has a perfect plan for all my body parts. Do you believe in that?</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Please pray that my eyes should always be fixed on God the father. Let me look unto Him in all circumstances of my life. Will you do that for me? Also pray that the word of my mouth as I begin to speak should be a pleasing sacrifice to God. And Mom , Dad I would love to be like David who was a man after God‘s own heart. Will you pray that I would be like one? “May the words of my mouth and the meditation of my heart be pleasing in your sight, O Lord my rock, and my redeemer” – Psalms 19:14 “I lift up my eyes to the hills where does my help come from?” – Psalms 121: 1</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Please pray that the works of my hands should be pure. Let me use my hands to praise God. I would like to play musical instruments with my hands and worship God. Why not pray for that in particular? “I wash my hands in innocence and go about your altar Oh Lord” - Psalms 26: 6</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Pray for the development of my fingers. They should be strong to face the battle ahead of me. I would like to have a good handwriting as I go to school. I think it‘s a bit ahead of me to think of it now. I think it‘s ok. And my teeth should be whiter ha ha ha! Will you pray Dad and Mom? “Praise be to the Lord my rock, who trains my hands for war, my fingers for battle” – Psalms 144:1 “His eyes will be darker than wine, his teeth whiter than milk” – Genesis 49:12</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Pray that I should hold His breathe in me as long as I live. My tongue should utter words that would praise Him and let it keep on uttering His holy scriptures. I would like to grow more in His word. Would you pray for that? As long as I have life within me, the breathe of God in my nostrils Job 27:3 My tongue will speak of your righteousness and your praises all day long – Psalms 35:28 May my tongue sing of your word – Psalms 119:172 Before a word is on my tongue, you know it completely Oh Lord– Psalms 139:4 Now claim these verses as you pray!</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Please pray for me claiming God‘s words. Scripture says that it has the power to penetrate my joins. Let me have a power penetrated first movement. Why don‘t you both pray over me with His promises? “For the word of God is living and active, sharper than any double edged sword, it penetrates even to dividing soul and spirit, joints and marrow; it judges the thoughts and attitudes of the heart” – Hebrews 4:12</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, I know that all the hairs of my head are numbered. Don‘t worry. God looks at me as the apple of His eye. Keep praying for me with good cheer. Is that ok? “Indeed the very hairs of your head are all numbered. Don‘t be afraid you are worth more than sparrows” – Luke 12:7 Pray that I have a beautiful hair as I grow.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Do not worry about my gender. Whether I am a boy or a girl I mean so much to you right? I was in the thoughts of God and that is why He has given me to you. Remember, Psalms 139:14 says, “I praise you because I am fearfully and wonderfully made; your works are wonderful, I know that full well”. Thank God for the purpose for which I was sent to you. Pray that you would faithfully raise me to fulfil the purpose God has in His mind for me.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, I am just reminded of this verse as I proudly look at you when you plan things for my growth. If you, then; though you are evil, know how to give good gifts to your children, how much more will your Father in heaven give good gifts to those who ask him! Matt 7:11. Don‘t worry I will grow to be a big person very soon. I love you both. Pray that I learn to pray and look unto God for all my needs.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Pleasant words are a honeycomb, sweet to the soul and healing to the bones – Proverbs 16:24. Yes! Why don‘t you start speaking kind words to me and as well to others? That would build our bones. For the word of God is alive and active. Sharper than any double-edged sword, it penetrates even to dividing soul and spirit, joints and marrow; it judges the thoughts and attitudes of the heart – Hebrews 4:12. Start speaking Bible verses to me. They would penetrate my joints and marrow! Pray that my bones would become stronger and stronger.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, As a mother comforts her child, so will I comfort you; and you will be comforted over Jerusalem. – Isaiah 66:13. That is how God honours motherhood. Yes, we have a long way to go in our life together me, Dad and Mom. As I start moving around pray that God would bless my journey out in the world and that He would guide and guard my steps.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, For I know the plans I have for you, declares the LORD, plans to prosper you and not to harm you, plans to give you hope and a future. – Jeremiah 29:11. God has got a plan for my life. He is bringing the best out of my life. Just wait for God‘s time to see me. This week many things are happening within me. Pray that I would advance into a troop with the strength that He gives me.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, As Psalms 34:10 says, ―He protects all their bones, not one of them will be broken. Pray that all my bones should be protected by the creator even as they begin to grow.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, As it is said in Psalms 139:2, ―You know when I sit and when I rise you perceive my thoughts from afar. God knows all my emotions. Do pray that God should help me to have emotional stability as I grow.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, As it is said in Song of Solomon 4:2 Your teeth are like a flock of sheep just shorn, coming up from the washing. Pray that my teeth should be beautiful.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, According to Galatians 5:22,23, ―But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness and self-control‖, pray for these characters to develop in me. Let my emotions bring joy to my Lord!</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, According to Psalms 31:19, which says, ―How great is your goodness, which you have stored up for those who fear you, which you bestow in the sight of all on those who take refuge in you. pray that I should always take refuge in God. And also pray that God would enable you to happily accept me whatever be the gender.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, According to Job 19:27, which says, ―I myself will see him with my own eyes—I, and not another. How my heart yearns within me! Let my eyes have a longing to see God. Pray that my heart is always sensitive to my Father God.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, According to Psalms 139:3, ―You discern my going out and my lying down; you are familiar with all my ways. Pray that God should direct my paths and my actions in life.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Matthew 18:14 reveals the heartbeat of God. It says, ―In the same way your Father in heaven is not willing that any of these little ones should perish. Pray that my heart beat should match with my Creator and that I should always do His will.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, As it is written in Psalms 150:6, ―Let everything that has breath praise the LORD. Praise the LORD. pray that His praise should always be on my lips</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, According 149:3 ―Let them praise his name with dancing and make music to him with timbrel and harp. Pray that I should be a good worshipper of God! Pray that I would sing praises to His wonderful name always and follow Him alone.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, According to Psalms 147:4, which says, ―He determines the number of the stars and calls them each by name, you know God has called me by my name. Are you now excited now to decide on my name? Pray that from now on till the end of my life I should hold God’s hands and walk in His ways. He has called be my name and He will lift me up.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, All the hairs of my head are counted. Yes that’s what the Bible says. Pray that I am blessed with a beautiful hair. I know God knows what would suit me. Why don’t you pray for how you wish it to be?</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, He has made everything beautiful in its time – Ecclesiastes 3:11. Yes God is waiting for His time. You know He is wonderfully dealing with me. Don‘t get excited too much. Just wait for His time to see me. Pray that God would meet all the needs for my arrival.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Trust in the LORD with all your heart and lean not on your own understanding‖ – Proverbs 3:5. Pray that I should grow in the fear of the Lord. More than the talents and gifts I possess its important to have a strong relationship with God. Don’t you think so. Pray that I would have a strong love relationship with God and obey Him completely.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Hold on to instruction; do not let it go; guard it well, for it is your life‖ – Proverbs 4:13. Pray and ask God that I should be a humble person ready to obey to the voice of God and of course to your instructions. Isn‘t that good to start doing it now?</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, I love those who love me, and those who seek me find me – Proverbs 8:17. Pray that I should be a good seeker. I know I would be able to learn more from your examples.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Whoever heeds discipline shows the way to life, but whoever ignores correction leads others astray – Proverbs 10:17. Pray that God should give me wisdom and grace to accept all disciplines. I want to be a disciplined person like you!</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, May he give you the desire of your heart and make all your plans succeed – Psalms 20:4. Pray that I should be a successful person in life.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Some trust in chariots and some in horses, but we trust in the name of the LORD our God – Psalms 20:7. Pray that I should always put my trust in God and not on others. I know you are also trusting God only for my safe arrival. I really appreciate that.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Surely your goodness and love will follow me all the days of my life, and I will dwell in the house of the LORD forever – Psalms 23:6. Why don‘t you claim this promise for me and pray together over my life. I would love that. ></item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, My eyes are ever on the LORD, for only he will release my feet from the snare – Psalms 25:15. Pray that my eyes should ever be on him. Start talking about God to me! Try to tell me stories and testimonies of how you got me as a gift from God. Yes Mom and Dad I love to hear you speak to me. I have recorded your voices</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, You will keep in perfect peace those whose minds are steadfast, because they trust in you – Isaiah 26:3. Pray that both of you should have good peace of mind these days. That is a great source of joy for me.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, The horse is made ready for the day of battle, but victory rests with the LORD – Proverbs 21:31. Now you have done all the preparations. Just wait with thanks giving. Wait on the Lord in prayer with thanksgiving.</item>
        <item>Dear Mom and Dad, Hope deferred makes the heart sick, but a longing fulfilled is a tree of life – Proverbs 13:12.Your long wait has ended. Great! Now lay hands on me pray and bless me</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="weeks" formatted="false">
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> This week begins with the last days of my Mom‘s menstrual period. I am nowhere on the scene. But you know I am in the thoughts of God. Let me start my story from here. Let me dedicate this week to you and call it Mom‘s week. Are you happy now? &lt;br> &lt;br> Soon we will be starting our journey together. Isn’t it amazing? I am in the thoughts of God and in your prayer list. I feel special cause you think about me before I am formed. And you know what Father God has big plans for me and He is creating me to fulfil His big plans! &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Hey mom you have no idea about me yet. I know that. But I know, both of you have dreamed of someone like me. And very soon I‘ll be there. Our nine – month love affair is about to begin. We have a long journey together. Even before we start let me warn you about my likes and dislikes. I like plenty of fruits and vegetables and I dislike smoking and alcohol. Tell this to everyone at home. I like simple exercises like going for long walks.&lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000>It is the second week and I am still in the thoughts of God. You know what? To say in short God is preparing my room for my stay for the next 10 months. What a loving Dad He is! I know you and Dad are going to try to show love like God. We are all made in His image right? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Your uterus is preparing a lush new bed of blood – rich tissue for me. One of the ripened eggs is getting ready to be released. Oops! I have started using medical terms. Hope they are not too difficult for you to understand. God has a plan for my life. He is sending me to you with a purpose. Yes Mom, my life is purpose driven. I am not an accident. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> The real drama begins now. Dad sent many sperms inside mom, but only one intrepid one, the fastest of all swimmers that were vying for that single egg of mom‘s … yes only one could penetrate its outer layer and has fertilized it. God has enabled the first step of my journey. Whatever physical or mental shape I am going to acquire tomorrow will be credited to you both Dad and mom. But you Dad will wholly determine my sex. Mom has nothing to do with it. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> You are not going to be alone any more. You are on the way of becoming a responsible Mom! Yes Mom, I am going to bring about a lot of changes in you physically and emotionally. Are you ready for the journey? Nothing comes without a price. Yes I know you are going to sacrifice so much on our journey together. I love you Mom! &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> The Blastocyst reaches the uterus and searches for a spot to settle down. Some call it the sprout bag. I call it my first home. The cells in the Blastocyst have begun to divide into two groups – those that form the placenta and those that form ―me. I measure only 0.1-0.2 mm in diameter. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> In case you are expecting your periods let me tell you, you will not get it. You are pregnant now. Of course some of the first pregnancy symptoms are very much similar to the premenstrual ones. You may feel restless, fatigue and mood swings. Don‘t panic, things will shortly change for the better. This week your excitement would start. Now I know you wouldn’t rest till you get a confirmation of my presence inside your tummy. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Oh Boy I am changing fat these days. I can hardly recognize myself. The developing ―me has three layers now. The top layer (ectoderm will be my nervous system i.e. the brain and spinal chord. The middle layer (mesoderm) will develop into the heart and circulatory system. For the development of intestines, liver, pancreas and bladder it is the lower layer or the endoderm that helps. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Are you wondering if you are pregnant? Those swollen breasts, nausea in the morning… and the dizzy spells? Your guess may be correct after all. Stay cool mom and take that much rest needed. Keep looking for the new likes and dislikes in you! &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> What‘s that funny faint sound? Oh my! It‘s actually coming from inside me – ‗ lub – dub – lub – dub‘. Bless my heart – they are my first heartbeats. Well, about time too – do you know how big I am now? I am about 1/17th of an inch (0.2 cm) my eyes and ears and a little opening in the mouth as well. Yes I am there. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> A little more of nausea and morning sickness? A craving for certain foods becoming more irresistible? Well, well, it‘s time to fix your first appointment with your antenatal doctor. Tell him straight if you have any symptoms like bleeding, cramps or abdominal pains. They might serve as warning signals for a miscarriage! And don‘t hide anything from the doctor. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am nearly the size of a grain of rice. Do I see a small smile on your face? No jokes – I am growing fast! My arms and legs can now be seen. My brain is growing too, getting bigger with each passing day. Its bom time for the eyes, nostrils, intestines and pancreas as well. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Are you worried about those few pounds you have gained or lost in the past few weeks? Oh don‘t worry mom, that‘s quite normal. Please don‘t start dieting – please! That makes me hungry. I eat whatever you eat. You know – that helps me grow faster. Stop worrying and start eating healthy diet ok? &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> Hey, do you know what I got this week? I got my elbows and my fingers. You think that‘s all? No, no, I‘ve got ears, eyes, teeth buds and the tip of the nose as well. What do you think of that now? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Did I hear you say, “My poor waist line”? Now that‘s an absolute waistline. Your waistline is growing because I am growing. I know you are worried about your looks – for those pimples and other skin problems you are getting. But you know they are happening due to an increase in oil secretions. I saw the doctor taking the measurement of your uterus the other day. I could almost feel it. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 3.1 cm by now, nearly the size of an olive. Something new is happening within me everyday. I can actually feel it in my bones and cartilage. I am beginning to get eyes and a small little tongue. The intestines are coming out of the umbilical cord and getting into my abdomen. That almost tickles me you know! The fingers and thumbs have appeared but are too tiny. I wish I could grow faster. This is taking a bit too long for my liking! &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> My home, your uterus has become the size of a grape fruit now. I know you got some heartburn and indigestion, the other day trying to adjust to the pregnancy hormones. Your breasts are getting fuller and have become very sensitive. I know that too. Don‘t tire yourself Mom; take a little rest; that makes me feel really good. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am about 4.6 cm by now and weigh around 5 gms. The joints guiding my internal movements are almost formed. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> You really can‘t make out why you feel so moody these days, don‘t you mom? Especially when nothing major has happened. The occasional dizziness accompanied by those headaches – are they getting you down? Blame it all on those wild hormones. &lt;br>&lt;br> But mom the morning sickness has eased up a bit isn‘t it? Veins are appearing on your tummy, breasts and the legs. I can see them. Don‘t let that bother you either. As the blood volume inside you increases, they develop. These are all indications that I am growing. So rejoice seeing those symptoms Mom. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 6 cm by now and weigh around 8 gms. By now I have got all the characteristics of a fetus. The most critical part of my development is over. The placenta has started to develop and blood has started to circulate between my mom‘s uterus and me. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> I bet you are feeling slightly better this week. Although certain smells still bother you, the nausea has subsided a bit and your appetite is increased. I know it because I wasn’t hungry this week. Your uterus can be felt in your lower abdomen. As you keep moving you have this feeling that you are already carrying me now. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 6.3 cm by now and I weigh around 8 to 14 Gms. Hey want some good news? I can pee now! Nearly all my organs are formed now. Fingers and toes have separated and hair and nails have begun to grow. Gosh – my gender is no more a secret! &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> There‘s good news for you too. The uterus is shifting forward as it grows, but it won‘t press on your bladder much. So those bathroom visits will get less frequent. That‘s good news isn‘t it? Morning sickness is also better. But you are going to gain weight in your hips and legs. I know the headaches are bothering you now. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 7.4 cm by now and I weigh around 23 gms. My eyes and ears are continuing to develop. My neck is getting longer! Hi Mom I can see the room I am staying in. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>Hey Mom you should start taking vitamins along with a healthy diet. Do you know something? I only get vitamins from what you eat. I know you are so excited to hear about this. Ask daddy to get nutritious food help to increase the nutritional values. Tell him that it’s for me! Ha ha ha.. Yes its true because I am going to eat from all that you eat. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 8.7 cm by now and I weigh around 43 Gms Oops I have doubled my weight. I think you are doing great job together in taking care of me. My bones are getting harder and stronger. My skin is still transparent and it really bothers me so much. Very fine hair is covering my body. This will shed only prior to my birth. It helps me to protect my skin. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>You might have some discomfort because of this growth in my body. Don‘t worry just few more weeks to go. You know something? If you are more than 35 years old, the Doctors will test you for Down‘s syndrome. Cool!! God is in control. Don’t have negative thoughts. Everything is going to be fine when God is with us. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 10.1 cm by now and I weigh around 70 Gms. I have started to move around. You can feel my presence every now and then. The three tiny bones in my ears have begun to harden. My eyebrows are beginning to grow. I am becoming beautiful as I always am. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>Your heart is increasing its output to supply me with oxygen. Your heart is pumping about 20% more blood than pre - pregnancy. This volume would increase throughout your pregnancy for an ending increased heart output of 30-50%. If your clothes are getting tight, do not try to cram yourself into clothes try maternity clothes. Remember I am growing!! Which means its ok for you to grow. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 11.6 cm by now and I weigh around 100 Gms. This is a week of ―mights. You might hear the tiny thumps of my heart with an external monitor now. The genitals are developed sufficiently that an experienced sonographer might be able to determine if I am a boy or a girl. Be it a boy or a girl you are going to love me isn’t it? &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>You may begin to feel my movement around this point. This is more likely to happen now if you already had a child before me or if you are very thin. Generally you will feel me move about one month earlier than you did in a previous pregnancy, mainly because you know what you are feeling. It is not uncommon for first time mothers to not recognize fetal movements until 22-24 weeks. These first movements are called ―quickening. They can also be used in helping to determine your due date. I am not going to stay still anymore. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 13 cm by now and I weigh around 140 Gms. I now have much more human appearance. My body limbs are larger in proportion to my head. Oops Meconium (digestive secretion and swallowed amniotic fluid) has started to gather. &lt;br>&lt;br>Umbilical cord is getting stronger. My skeleton is transforming from cartilage to bone. The bone still remains flexible to make the journey through the birth canal easier. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>Your uterus is now about halfway between your pubic bone and navel. Your secretions all over your body may increase, due to the increased blood volume. If you are sweating more, have nasal congestion, or suffering from increased vaginal discharge this is nothing to worry about and will go away after the birth of the baby. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 14.2 cm by now and I weigh around 190 Gms. Vernix (a white cheese – like protective material) is forming on my skin to protect my skin during the months in water. See how creative my shepherd is! Tiny air sacs have begun to form in my lungs. I will be putting my lungs to good use in just a few months. I can go through a motion of crying but without air I cannot make sound. Fast growth this week which means tired week for you! &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>Do not forget to take your prenatal vitamins Mom! Sleeping may be increasingly difficult now, as your body grows. Try supporting yourself with pillows to help you find a more comfortable sleeping position. You might also try doing pelvic tilts before bed, and always urinate before lying down. If you haven't started yet, try playing around with baby names. Look through your family history, read books, look at combinations for girls and boys. And if you have a promise from God name me in faith. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 15.3 cm by now and I weigh around 240 Gms. I now have the same awake and sleep patterns of a new born. I have a favourite position for sleep and recognizable active and rest periods. Are you able to find it out mom? Milk teeth buds have already developed and over the next few days buds for the permanent teeth will begin to form behind it. In case I am a girl, my uterus starts to develop this week. If I am a boy the genitals are now distinct and recognizable. You know something? I am swallowing amniotic fluid and my kidneys are making urine. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>If you have not looked into childbirth classes now is the time to do so. Child birth education is a great way of informing yourself about pregnancy, labor and birth. There are many different types of classes available and many different types of teachers. Find a class that best fits your schedule. Some classes meet for a few hours every week for several weeks, while other meet for an intense period of time over one or two days. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 16.4 cm by now and I weigh around 300 Gms. I am half way there. The rapid growth stage is over. Even though things have slowed down, this next stage is vital to survival. The nerve cells for taste, smell, hearing, seeing and touch are now developing in specialized areas of the brain. I can actually hear noises outside the womb. If I am a girl I now have approximately six million eggs in my ovaries and about one million would remain at birth. My creator is very creative. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>Find a quiet place; lay flat on your back. Locate your own heart beat by finding your pulse. Next lay your hand on your belly. You would be able to distinguish between my heart beat and yours. As muscles are developing you would be able to feel my kicks even stronger. I can listen to sounds. Familiar voices, music and sounds that I become accustomed to during developmental stages often are calming at birth. Watch out for what you hear. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000>I am around 26.7 cm by now and I weigh around 360 Gms. White blood cells are under production in my body. They help in fighting infections and diseases. My skin has become more opaque. My tongue is fully formed. I am swallowing amniotic fluid. I am putting myself into digestion practice. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>Everyone is probably telling you what sex your baby is using different myths! Some people find this fun, others find it annoying. Using things like how you carry, what you eat, the Chinese Gender Chart, or other myths are fun, but not always accurate. Have you decided whether you want to find out the gender of your baby? There are many things to consider before doing so, and still I may not cooperate. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 27.8 cm by now and I weigh around 430 Gms. I can now hear your conversations more clearly than before. When you talk, read or sing remember I am hearing you. My eye lids and eye brows are fully formed. Finger nails have grown. &lt;br>&lt;br>My brain has entered a stage of rapid growth. Why don’t you keep singing His praises to me? My heart would rejoice to do that Mom. &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>You are still feeling pretty good and active in this second trimester. If you are still having aches and pains or feel like you are slowing down you may want to look into some different remedies for the problems you're experiencing. With God’s strength you can do it well Mom. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 28.9 cm by now and I weigh around 501 Gms. I almost look like a new born but I am thinner. I am able to hear. My eyes are formed. I have begun producing Insulin, important for break down of sugars. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>You may begin to feel my movement around this point. This is more likely to happen now if you already had a child before me or if you are very thin. Generally you will feel me move about one month earlier than you did in a previous pregnancy, mainly because you know what you are feeling. &lt;br>&lt;br>It is not uncommon for first time mothers to not recognize fetal movements until 22-24 weeks. These first movements are called ―quickening. They can also be used in helping to determine your due date. I am not going to stay still anymore. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 30 cm by now and I weigh around 600 Gms almost a length of a ruler. My body begins to fill out with my appearance more like a new born. My taste buds are beginning to form. Over the next seven days sweat gland will be forming in the skin. This week I am officially considered viable. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>You are now aware of my movements and may even be able to tell the sleep/wake cycles of your little one. It is important to recognize the signs of premature labour. Premature labour is actually more common in the summer months, thought to be caused by dehydration in some women, so continue drinking lots of water! &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 34.6 cm by now and I weigh around 660 Gms. Structures of my spine have begun to form. Blood vessels of the lungs are developing. My nostrils have begun to open. My swallowing reflexes are developing. I can now make a fist and can clasp objects placed in my palm. I am excited I am learning to do new things. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>At this point in pregnancy you probably still feel really good! Soon you will begin to see your practitioner more often. When this happens, many women begin to get the feeling that they are running out of time. &lt;br>&lt;br>Fixing my room or deciding where I sleep, is one of the things you need to work out now. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 35.6 cm by now and I weigh around 760 Gms. Air sacs in my lungs are forming now. My eyes are opening and beginning to blink this week.Retinas begin to form. My brain wave activity for hearing and sight begins to be detectable. &lt;br>&lt;br>If you shine a light on your abdomen mom, I will turn my head, which means my optic nerve is working. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>While you have been feeling movements for a while, those other people in your life may not have been able to. Around this time it may become possible for them to begin feeling the baby from the outside. It is really nice to share the experience with others. &lt;br>&lt;br>Finding a comfortable position for sleeping is a new task! Between night time waking to go to the bathroom, to get water or snacks, you need all the sleep you can get. A body pillow will enable you to support your legs and your growing belly! If you don't have one, try making use of several regular pillows. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 36.6 cm by now and I weigh around 875 Gms. My brain continues its rapid growth. My hearing continues to develop. I have started to recognize your voice and Dad‘s mom! That‘s interesting right? My lungs are continuing to grow and prepare for functioning outside of the womb. I am continuing to take small breaths. My eye lids are now open more. This week alone I will grow over 1 inch. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Mom you can now share music, conversation and even books with me. Welcome to the third trimester. The home stretch! Around this time you will begin to really put on the weight, this will last until about week thirty-six. Although some cultures dictate otherwise, weight gained during pregnancy is not fat or unhealthy, but rather, necessary for a healthy pregnancy and baby. &lt;br>&lt;br>The weight that you gain will be distributed in several places. The average breast before pregnancy weighs about 7 ounces (200 g) and during pregnancy each breast can weigh up to an average of 28 ounces (800 g)! Some of the weight will go to body fluids (amniotic fluid, blood volume, etc.). &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 37.6 cm by now and I weigh around 1 Kg. My eye brows and eye lashes are now very noticeable. Hair on my head is growing longer. Some babies are born with almost none at all, while others appear to be ready for their first hair cut. My eyes are completely formed now. My body is getting plump and rounded. Lungs are capable of breathing now. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>You can talk to me often, read stories, and sing songs and so on. I can recognize your voice now and will often calm to it later on. Keep talking to me. I really love that. If you have taken childbirth classes you have a good idea of the interventions and alternatives associated in childbirth. &lt;br>&lt;br>Your breasts may leak colostrum now, although if they do not leak, this is not an indication that you can't breastfeed. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 38.6 cm by now and I weigh around 1153 Gms. My head is in proportion with my body now. Fat continues to accumulate under my skin. My brain can control primitive breathing and body temperatures. My eyes can move in their sockets. I am increasingly sensitive to changes in light, sound, taste and smell! I am now moving from side to side. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>Mom as I have started to move sometimes you might even wonder thinking that I am performing somersaults for a circus act. As your baby is growing, so is your body. You may feel as if your internal organs are crowded. They are. &lt;br>The best way to deal with the ―discomforts of pregnancy is &lt;br>• Good Posture &lt;br>• Proper Nutrition &lt;br>• Exercise &lt;br>• Rest (When you can!) &lt;br>Most discomforts will occur in your back, your legs, and the amount of air you can take into your lungs. Hang in there! &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 39.9 cm by now and I weigh around 1319 Gms. My head is getting larger to accommodate a period of rapid brain growth. As I grow and fill your uterus, the amount of amniotic fluid will decrease. Mom you won‘t feel lighter any more. I spend more time practicing opening and closing my eye lids. &lt;br>&lt;br>My toe nails are entering into final growth stage. Bone marrow is now producing red blood cells. I now have the capacity to produce tears – within the womb. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>Your posture is still very important to your comfort. Maintaining a good posture is a good way to decrease the strain on your body as your center of gravity continues to change. &lt;br>&lt;br>One of the things that you can do to help maintain your energy levels and to increase your stamina for the birth is to exercise. Try taking walks or swimming short distances. Getting out and stretching will help you have feel better and reduce the numbers of pregnancy related complaints. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 41.1 cm by now and I weigh around 1502 Gms. The rate of my physical growth slows down. Even though I don‘t grow much longer, my weight keeps increasing. Fat continues to accumulate. Calcium, Phosphorus and iron being stored in my body and my bones are growing and hardening. My brain has entered another period of rapid growth, producing hundreds of billions of nerve cells! Amazing! I may move to the rhythm of music. Lungs are the only major organ left to complete development. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>Your abdomen swells and your rib cage and pelvis may be sore as the baby gets bigger and fills up all the space you have available. While it is really great that your baby is gaining weight and growing strong, you may be in line for different discomforts at this stage of the game, like heart burn and leg cramps &lt;br>&lt;br>A few women will breeze by even this phase of pregnancy without any discomforts. This does not mean that your body isn't preparing for birth. It could be pain tolerance levels, exercise and agility levels and many other factors. So, count your blessings if you fall into this category! &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 42.4 cm by now and I weigh around 1702 Gms. All my senses (all the 5) are now working. I am fascinated and practicing testing these out as much as possible. Hair on my head continues to grow in. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>I want to address the last question specifically. About 10% of women will tell you that labour is extremely painful, while 10% of the women will tell you that they experienced no pain. The rest, 80%, will fall someplace in the middle of the two extremes. &lt;br>&lt;br>But don‘t worry mom, ―God is with you as a mighty terrible one. You can cross this valley happily with God’s grace. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 43.7 cm by now and I weigh around 1918 Gms. My head size has increased 3/8ths of an inch due to rapid brain growth. Neurons and synapses are developing in huge numbers – forming connections in my brain will give me the skills I need to thrive as a new born. This week I may be able to coordinate sucking and swallowing with breathing. My skull is quite pliable and not completely joined. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>You can now probably distinguish my knee from and elbow, even though the movements are smaller. You may also notice small bumps that appear to be rhythmic in your uterus. This is probably caused by me having hiccoughs and isn't cause for alarm &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 45cm by now and I weigh around 2146 Gms. I almost behave like a new born now my eyes opened when I am awake and closed when sleeping. I am settled with a regular sleeping time now. I have learned to blink. I have already turned to a head down position in preparation for birth. Finger nails have reached the end of the finger tips. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000>Do you know something? I can see more clearly when there is a bright light on your stomach and probably I have the outline of all your organs memorized. Antibodies from your blood are being transferred to me. This bond between us continues till birth. Your body is really getting ready and you may notice that you have more and more contractions that seem less and less like practice! This is a great sign that your body is getting ready! &lt;br>Labour is broken down into three stages: &lt;br>• First stage - contractions that open the cervix. &lt;br>• Second stage - pushing the baby out. &lt;br>• Third stage - birthing the placenta &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 46.2 cm by now and I weigh around 2383 Gms. Most babies born now will survive and without any long term problems. Fat accumulations plumps up my arms and legs this week. . These layers of fat help me to regulate my body temperature. They also provide that cute little dimple on elbows and knees. My hearing is fully developed. I am now taking up most of the uterus. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> You may even feel like your chest has run short of room. Soon enough though, I will move down and you will be able to breathe easily. Your pregnancy is progressing and you may have trouble sleeping at night. Some claim that this is Mother Nature‘s way of preparing you for life with a new baby. Others believe it is caused by worrying about the health of your baby, labor, and/or parenting. There are also numerous physical reasons that sleep may be difficult. &lt;br> &lt;br> For one going the bathroom every 45 minutes isn't conducive to sleep, nor is a constant back ache. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 47.4 cm by now and I weigh around 2622 Gms. The only organ still to mature is the lungs. Each day the baby stays within the womb, it will multiply its chances to breathe on its own. This week the Baby may drop into the birth canal. Skin is growing smooth; call it ―baby soft. The Baby has fully developed pair of kidneys. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> While breathing for mom becomes easier walking may be the exact opposite. Most babies will be in a head down position at this point. However, about 4% of the babies will be breech. &lt;br>&lt;br> Do not panic! There are plenty of things that you can do to encourage the baby to turn, including special exercises. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 48.6 cm by now and I weigh around 2859 Gms. The baby is officially full term now but can still benefit from extra days in the womb. Your baby continues to practice breathing movements. &lt;br>&lt;br> If God gives me some more time for me to jump around your belly I would happily do it Mom. I tell you I love this first home of mine. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> A pregnancy is considered a term pregnancy at this point and nothing will be done to stop labour in most circumstances. You should plan to take a tour of your birth facility if you have not previously. &lt;br>&lt;br> If you are having a home birth try to invite everyone over for a quick run through of what you expect. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 49.8 cm by now and I weigh around 3083 Gms. The baby‘s intestines are accumulating lots of Meconium. Meconium takes on the role of being your baby‘s first bowel movement – removing the waste that has accumulated. Circumference of head and abdomen are about the same size for the Baby &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> You may begin to feel electrical buzzes down your legs and inside your vagina. This is caused from the baby hitting nerves as s/he settles into your pelvis. &lt;br>&lt;br>It is also usually encouraged that you bring a separate support person for the child (ren) so that they may come and go during labour and you won't be concerned. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>"&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 50.7 cm by now and I weigh around 3288 Gms. My lungs are maturing and fully I am preparing to take on the outside world. In addition to normal fat, I am accumulating a special ―brown fat in the nape of my neck, between my shoulders and around organs. Brown fat cells are important for thermo genesis (generating heat) during his first weeks. &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Now that you know how to tell if you are really in labour, let's talk about some of the ways your body prepares for labour. Your baby will descend into your pelvis, sometimes called engagement or lightening, usually before labour in first time moms and during labour in subsequent births. &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>"</item>
        <item>&lt;font color=#000000> I am around 51.2 cm by now and I weigh around 3462 Gms. 15 percent of my body is fat. Since I havent learnt to shiver yet, these fat stores will help in regulating my temperature. Approximately 60 – 75 percent is water! &lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#318CE7>Are you listening mom?&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br> &lt;font color=#000000> Congratulations! Any day now you will be cradling your son or daughter! Cherish the moments and learn all you can about this new personality in your life &lt;br>&lt;/font>&lt;/b> &lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;center> Happy Parenting!!! &lt;/center>&lt;b>&lt;font color=#0000FF>click here for prayer for the week&lt;/font>&lt;/b>&lt;br></item>
    </string-array>
</resources>
